# **Curtis Bowser**

bwsrcurtis@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | CodePen | Salisbury, Maryland | (443) 799 1122

#### **About Me**

I am a full stack developer who works primarily with React and NextJS, however, I consider myself to be platform agnostic. Different technologies work better with different projects, so it is important to have exposure to many different things. I also have experience writing code in Python for automation.

## **Technologies and Languages**

- Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Frameworks: NextJS, React, Bootstrap, NodeJS
- Tools: SQL, Git, Github, MongoDB, Prisma

#### **Education**

• Google Data Analytics Prof. Cert., Google

Oct 2021

B.Sc. Economics, Towson University, Towson, MD

June 2019

### **Projects**

- Gardienne (In Progress) (Full-Stack): Gardienne helps users manage their plants' watering times and improve their health by sending reminders and suggestions. It uses NextJS, React, NextAuth for user authentication, NodeJS, Prisma, and a MongoDB database for storing user information.
- Photography Site (Live Site) (React): This site was built in React and uses Material UI components to display photography. Uses hooks to filter by category and user selection.
- <u>React Pokédex (Live Site)</u> (React): This was built using React with hooks after retrieving the data from the Pokémon API. Users can select and search for Pokémon and brings up information for their choice.
- <u>Portfolio</u> (JS): Features include a dark mode and contact sheet implemented in JavaScript. The site is built from the ground up with HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- <u>Various CodePen Projects</u> (Misc): A collection of small projects, such as a drawing app, BMI calculator, random quote generator, background color changer, and CSS styling examples.
- <u>Sentiment Predictor</u> (Machine Learning): Cleaned raw text review data for machine learning, split data into test and training sets, and built Random Forest Classifier which evaluated to 74% accuracy.

## **Work Experience**

Driver DoorDash Dec 2020 - Present

Glen Burnie, MD

Delivered great customer satisfaction with a 5-star rating and zero complaints over my tenure

Streamer Twitch Aug 2019 – Dec 2020

Glen Burnie, MD

- Grew a community from zero to 150 followers by increasing awareness through social media and networking
- Used viewer data to plan future relevant content

Shift Supervisor Banner Hallmark May 2015 – Dec 2016

Annapolis, MD

- Supervised five employees while addressing concerns and reaching daily goals responsibility
- Developed training material to more efficiently onboard new hires